[ Crowd Sounds ]
[人声]
[ Applause ]
[掌声]
&gt;&gt; Good morning, everyone.
&gt;&gt; 大家早上好
Welcome to VR with Metal 2.
欢迎来到 VR with Metal 2
My name is Rav Dhiraj, and I'm a
我是 Rav Dhiraj
member of the GPU Software Team
是 Apple GPU 软件团队的一员
So, as you saw in our
大家都已经在
Introducing Metal 2 Session,
Introducing Metal 2 讲座中了解到
we've enabled some great new
我们今年又推出了不少
features this year.
新特性
And in this session, I'll be
在这场演讲中 我将会
focusing specifically on the
特别集中讲一下
support for VR that we're adding
我们在 Metal 2 中添加的
with Metal 2.
对 VR 的支持
So, I'll start with a brief
首先 我想简短总结一下
summary of what we've enabled in
我们在 macOS High Sierra 中
macOS High Sierra.
推出的新功能
And then, take a deep dive into
然后再深入讲解
what's required to build a VR
构建 VR App 有哪些要求
And then, end by providing some
最后 再仔细讲一下
details on how you can take
你们可以如何利用
advantage of the new external
我们在 OS 中添加的
GPU support that we've added to
最新的外接 GPU 支持
the OS.
这项功能
All right.
好了
I hope everyone here knows what
我希望大家已经都知道
virtual reality is.
虚拟现实是什么了
But just in case, it's am
但为防万一 我还是解释一下
immersive 360-degree 3D
它是一种沉浸式的 360 度 3D
experience, with direct object
体验 可以通过控制器
manipulation using controllera.
直接操控物体
And an interactive room sized
还有一个房间大小的
environment that you can
交互环境供人探索
explore, thanks to highly
这要多亏了
accurate motion tracking.
高度精确的动作追踪
Now, we at Apple think that this
我们 Apple 认为
is a great new medium for
VR 对于在座的开发者来说
developers like you to create
是一个为用户创造新体验的
new experiences for our users.
很棒的媒介
And Metal 2 enables this support
Metal 2 以三种方式
in three ways.
为此提供支持
First, by providing a fast path
首先 提供一个快速 panel
to present the frame directly to
让画面帧直接显示
the VR headset with our new
在 VR 头戴显示器上 这用到了新的
Direct to Display capability.
Direct to Display 功能
Second, by enabling new features
其次 推出特别为 VR
like Viewport Array that are
设计的新功能
specifically targeting VR.
比如 Viewport Array
And finally, by providing that
最后 为外接 GPU
foundational support for
提供基础支持
external GPUs, so that
以便开发者能够
developers have a broader range
使用更多样的
of Mac hardware.
Mac 硬件
Of VR capable Mac hardware to
支持 VR 的 Mac 硬件
work on.
进行工作
So, let's get right into what
好了 我们现在开始
we've enabled with macOS High
讲解 macOS High Sierra
Sierra.
的新功能
So, we've added built-in plug
我们添加了对于 HTC ViveVR 头戴显示器
and play support for the HTC
的即插即玩功能
Vive VR headset.
这是内置的
And this headset works in
这个头戴显示器
conjunction with Valve SteamVR
与 Valve SteamVR runtime
runtime, which provides a number
一起工作 提供了一系列功能
of services, including the VR
其中就包括 VR
compositor.
compositor （矫正器）
Valve is also bringing their
Valve 还把他们的
open VR APIs to macOS, so that
OpenVR API 添加进了 macOS
you guys can create VR apps that
这样你们就能创造与 SteamVR
work with SteamVR.
兼容的 VR App了
We've been working really
我们在去年
closely with Valve over the last
与 Valve 密切合作
year to align our releases, and
协调我们的发布
both SteamVR and OpenVR are
现在 SteamVR 和 OpenVR
available to download in beta
的 beta 版本都可以下载了
form, this week.
就在这周
So, before I go on, I'd like to
在继续之前
describe what the VR compositor
我想讲一下 VR compositor
actually does.
的具体功能
So, in a nutshell, it distorts
一言以蔽之
the image that your app renders
它会让你的 App 渲染的画面失真
to account for the lens optics
以配合 VR 头戴显示器中的透镜
in the VR headset.
从而显示出正常的画面
In this example, you can see the
在这个示例中 你们可以看到
barrel distortion that the
compositor 用桶形失真
compositor is applying to
来抵消透镜
account for the pincushion
的枕形畸变效果
Now, in practice, there's
在实际应用中
actually a lot more complexity
会比这个示例
under the covers.
复杂得多
And the compositor had to handle
compositor 需要去
things like chromatic
处理色差现象
aberration, and also presenting
还要呈现一个
a Chaperone UI, so that
Chaperone UI
developers know the bounds of
以便开发者们能够了解
their VR space.
他们的 VR 空间的边界
All right.
好了
Now, that you have built-in
现在你有了对 VR 头戴显示器的
support for a VR headset, a VR
内置支持 有了
compositor with SteamVR, and an
SteamVR 的 VR compositor
API to write to, let's dive
还有了 API 框架
right into how you build a VR
下面我们就开始深入讲解如何创造
app.
VR App
Well, we have two options.
我们有两种选择
You first, is to use an existing
第一是使用现有的
game engine that has VR support.
支持 VR 的游戏引擎
This is a great option that many
这是很多开发者喜欢的
developers prefer, because it
很好的选择 因为它
hides some of the complexities
把 VR compositor 的一些复杂性
of the VR compositor.
隐藏起来了
It also provides a familiar
同时它也提供了一个熟悉的
content creation tool chain.
内容创造工具链
Now, your second option, is to
那么第二个选择
write a native VR app that calls
是写一个原生的 VR App
open VR, directly.
直接调用 openVR
This gives your app full control
这会让你的 App 能够用
of rendering and synchronization
VR compositor 全面控制
with the VR compositor.
渲染与同步
But at the cost of some
但要以一些额外的复杂性
additional complexity.
作为这样做的代价
Which path you take depends on
选择哪一种方法取决于
the goals of your app.
你的 App 的目标
Let's start by talking a bit
我们先来说一说
about the game engines.
游戏引擎吧
So, you saw Epic's Unreal Engine
你们在主旨演讲中已经见到
4 in action in the keynote, and
Epic 公司的虚幻4引擎的实用
it's a powerful platform on
这是个强有力的平台
which to build your VR
在上面可以构建你的 VR
experiences.
体验
VR support will be coming later,
对于 VR 的支持会在今年晚些时候
this year, and you can find
推出 你还可以在 Epic 的官网上找到
tutorials and other information
教程以及其他
on Epic's website.
相关信息
We're also really excited that
我们还很高兴地看到
Unity is bringing VR support to
Unity 也会在未来的引擎版本中
macOS in a future release of
在 macOS 中加入对 VR 的支持
We've been working closely with
我们正与他们密切合作
them to ensure that the engine
以确保引擎为
is optimized for both VR
VR 回放和使用 Metal 开发
playback and development using
进行了优化
So, I'd like to take a moment,
说到这里
at this point, to talk about a
我想用一些时间谈谈
specific Unity title called
一个特别的 Unity 游戏 那就是
Space Pirate Trainer.
Space Pirate Trainer
So, we've been collaborating
我们与 Unity 和 I-Illusions 合作
with Unity and I-Illusions to
把 Space Pirate Trainer
bring an early preview of Space
的一个早期版本
Pirate Trainer to macOS.
带入了 macOS
And the speed at with I-Illusion
I-Illusion 把他们的 App
was able to bring their app to
放到我们的平台上的速度
our platform was truly
真是非常惊人
astounding.
他们只用了几小时
a few hours, then a stable fully
就完成了可运行的版本
playable game in just a handful
几天内就推出了完全可游玩的
of days.
正式版本
We've been having tremendous fun
我们玩这个游戏
playing with this game, and
玩得不亦乐乎
think that it's a great
而且我们认为
representation of the type of VR
这个游戏很好地
experience that you can build
代表了你们用 Unity 可以
with unity.
构建出的 VR 体验
We hope you get a chance to
我们希望你们能够通过 WWDC
check it out at WWDC.
来了解一下
We think you'll love it, as
我们相信你们一定会也爱上它的
So, Unity and Unreal Engine 4
Unity 和虚幻 4 引擎
are two great options for VR
是 VR 开发的两大优秀平台
But you can, of course, choose
但是你们当然也可以
to write a native SteamVR app,
选择去写一个原生的 SteamVR App
that calls the open VR
直接调用
framework, directly.
OpenVR 框架
Now, we'll have details on how
我们会详细讲到
you can add the framework to
要如何把这个框架添加进
your app, later in the session.
你们的 App 这场演讲后面会讲到
But you can download binaries
你们可以在 OpenVR GitHub 上
and API documentation at the
下载到二进制代码和
OpenVR GitHub.
API 文档
There'll also be a Metal
很快还会有一个
specific sample app available to
针对 Metal 的范例 App
download in the near future.
可供下载
But to give you a taste of
现在 为了给大家一个基本概念
what's involved, I'd like to
我想先提供一个 VR App
now, provide a primer on VR app
开发的基础讲解
development in a segment that I
这个环节 我想把它叫做
like to call VR App Building
VR App 构建入门
So, we're going to cover a few
我们将会讲到
things, here.
以下几点
We'll start with an overview of
首先是在 VR 开发
some of the challenges involved
过程中会遇到的
in VR development.
一些挑战
And then, talk a bit about some
然后会讲一点
unique considerations on our
我们的平台上的独有特点
And then, take a deep dive into
然后是深入剖析
the anatomy of a VR frame.
VR 框架
And then, end with some best
最后 以一些针对
practices specific to VR apps.
VR App 的最佳范例作为结尾
So, we've got a lot to cover,
所以 我们要讲的很多
here.
就先从概况开始吧
So, a traditional non-VR work
在 60 Hz 显示下
load targeting a 60Hz display
传统的非 VR 动画
has around 16.7 milliseconds to
每一帧大约有 16.7 毫秒的时间
do work for the frame.
供你使用
And in many cases, the app has
在很多情况下 App 可以
the entire frame budget to do
把整个帧的时间预算用在
work on the GPU.
GPU 运算上面
A VR workload, on the other
但是 VR 工作
hand, has to target a 90 frame
必须要针对每秒 90 帧
per second display.
的显示方式
And it needs to hit this target
这样才能
to achieve a smooth stutter-free
在 Vive 这样的头戴显示器上
experience on a headset like the
达到流畅无卡顿的
Vive.
显示效果
So, this reduces the available
这就把每帧的时间
frame budget to around 11
压缩到了 11 毫秒左右
Additionally, the VR compositor
此外 VR compositor
has to do work on the GPU to
还要用 GPU 为
prepare the frame for the VR
VR 头戴显示器的失真
headset.
做调整
This can take up to 1
这大约需要 1 毫秒
millisecond, leaving you app an
这就让你的 App
effective frame time budget of
每帧可利用的时间
around 10 milliseconds.
缩短到了 10 毫秒
Which is about 60% of the non-VR
相当于非 VR 工作的
case.
60%
And if that wasn't enough, your
这还没完
app also has to do more work
你的 App 在每一帧
every frame.
还有其它工作
This includes stereo rendering
包括左右眼画面的
for the left and right eye.
立体渲染
And also, rendering to a higher
很多情况下还包括
resolution, in many cases.
高分辨率的渲染工作
The Vive headset has a
Vive 头显设备的分辨率是
resolution of 2160 x 1200.
2160 x 1200
That's 25% more pixels than a
这比1080的高清标准
1080 display.
还多出 25% 的像素
Additionally, many VR apps
此外 很多 VR App
render at a 1.2 to 1.4 X scale
还会以 1.2 到 1.4 倍的画面比例
factor to further improve
进行渲染 以保证高质量的画面
So, in summary, your app has a
也就是说 你的 App
lot more work to do in less
要在更少的时间内做更多工作
Welcome to VR development.
欢迎来到 VR 开发的世界
All right.
好了
Let's talk about some platform
我们来说一说平台的具体特点吧
So, Metal 2 introduces a new
Metal 2 推出了一项新的
Direct to Display capability for
Direct to Display 功能
supported headsets like the
用在其支持的头显设备上 比如
Vive.
Vive
This is a low latency path that
这是一个低延迟通道
bypasses the OS window
绕过了 OS window
compositor, and gives the VR
compositor 并给予 VR
compositor, like SteamVR, the
compositor 比如 SteamVR
direct ability to present a
直接在头显设备上
surface onto the VR headset.
显示画面的能力
This avoids any pixel processing
这一功能避免了 OS 去做
or additional copies by the OS.
像素处理或是额外拷贝
Now, it's worth noting that in
如果为了保证这条快速通道
order to guarantee this fast
让 macOS 不把 VR 头显设备
path, that macOS does not treat
当成显示设备
VR headsets as displays.
那它将一文不值 毫无意义
They're hidden from the system
它们会被隐藏在系统里
and offer no extended desktop
无法提供任何扩展的
capabilities.
桌面功能
So, to summarize, we move from a
总结一下 以前的模型
model where you can present or
是你可以 或者说一个 App
an app presents to a display
可以通过操作系统的
through the OS window
window compositor 来显示画面
To one where a VR app can
现在则是一个 VR App
present to a headset directly
直接通过 VR compositor
through the VR compositor.
在头显设备上显示画面
And that's our Direct to Display
这就是 Metal 2 为了 VR
capability for VR with Metal 2.
推出的 Direct to Display 功能
All right.
好了
Keeping with the theme of macOS
我们继续 macOS 平台特点的话题
platform specifics, let's talk a
我们来说一说你们的 App
bit about how your app selects a
如何选择 metal 设备
Metal device to use.
进行工作
So, in macOS, the VR compositor
在 macOS 里 VR compositor
can query the OS to find the
可以要求 OS
Metal device for the GPU that
为与头显设备相连的 GPU
the headset is attached to.
寻找设备
And for performance reasons,
出于性能方面的考虑
your app will want to select the
你的 App 会选择与
same device that the compositor
compositor 正在使用的设备
is using.
相同的设备
So, we've worked with Valve to
我们与 Valve 共同工作
make sure that there's an API to
以确保有一个 API
do this, simply called
负责这一点 它就是
GetOutputDevice to get the Metal
GetOutputDevice 它能找到
device that you should render
作为你渲染目标的 Metal 设备
It's that simple.
就这么简单
Now, let's talk about managing
接下来 我们说一下在 macOS 上
drawable surfaces on macOS.
管理 drawable 表面的问题
So, the VR compositor and your
VR compositor 和你的 App
app each maintain separate pools
为 drawable 表面分别保留了
of drawable surfaces.
不同的 pool
And in a typical frame your app
在典型的一帧画面里 你的 App 会
will render to textures that it
把它渲染成它所具有的纹理
owns, submit these to the VR
再提交给
compositor.
VR compositor
These will get composited onto a
然后这些会被合成到
surface that the compositor
compositor 所具有的一个表面
owns, and that's the surface
这个表面将会
that'll get presented to the
显示在头戴设备上
And on macOS, IO surfaces are
在 macOS 中 把这些
ideal for transferring this
经过渲染的数据
rendered data from your app to
从你的 App 转移到 compositor 上
the compositor.
IO surface 是理想的媒介
So, make sure that you create
所以请确保你们制作的
Metal textures that are backed
Metal 纹理要得到
by IO surfaces.
IO surface 的支持
As a refresher, let's take a
我们来看看
quick look at how you create
你要如何制造
those textures.
这些纹理
So, you'll want to build a
你要建立一个
texture descriptor that
纹理描述符
specifies the Render Target
指明渲染目标
Usage flag, since your app will
使用标志 因为你的 App
be rendering into it.
会对它进行渲染
But also, the Shader Read Usage
但也要有着色器读取使用标志
Since the compositor will be
因为 compositor 会把它
sourcing it as an input.
作为一个输入
And then, to create your left
然后 要制作左右眼
and right eye Textures, you
纹理 你只需要把之前分配的
simply pass IO surfaces that you
IO surface 和这个
previously allocated and this
纹理描述符
Texture descriptor to
传送给
newTextureWithDescriptor.
newTextureWithDescriptor 就可以了
All right.
好的
I'd like to now, take a few
现在我想花几分钟时间
minutes to talk or to describe a
讲一下 或者说描述一下
typical frame in a VR app.
VR App 中的典型一帧
This is important, because your
这很重要 因为你的 App
app and the VR compositor need
和 VR compositor 必须要
to work in lock step.
同步工作
As I noted before, the rendered
我之前说过
output of your app will be
你的 App 渲染后的输出
passed to the VR compositor for
要被传送到 VR compositor 里
additional processing on the
用 GPU 进行额外的处理
And since the GPU is a shared
因为 GPU 属于共享资源
resource, synchronization and
因此保持同步与安排工作时间
when work is scheduled matters.
就非常重要了
So, let's start at the beginning
我们就从一帧的开头
of the frame.
说起吧
Your app will need to query the
你的 App 需要请求
VR system to get the headset
VR 系统 获取头显设备
poses that it needs to render
的动作 它需要这个来渲染
the frame.
这一帧
For SteamVr, this is done by the
对 SteamVR 来说 这是用
WaitGetPoses call.
WaitGetPoses 调用来完成的
And then, your app can encode
然后你的 App
the rendered commands for that
在获得这些输入后
frame immediately after getting
可以立即对这一帧渲染后的命令
those inputs.
进行编码
And then, once you've encoded
然后 在你在对命令缓冲
your command buffer, you can
进行编码后
commit it to Metal to queue onto
你可以将它提交给 Metal
the GPU.
在 GPU 上排队
And then, submit your left and
然后 将你的左右眼纹理
right eye textures to SteamVR.
提交给 SteamVR
This'll wake the compositor so
这会唤起 compositor
it can start encoding its GPU
让它开始为这一帧的
work for the frame.
GPU 工作进行编码
And then, since ordered
然后 因为执行顺序非常重要
execution matters, your app will
你的 App 还需要
also need to signal the VR
告诉 VR compositor
compositor when work that is
交给 GPU 的工作
sent to the GPU has been
被安排在何时开始
So, for a Metal SteamVR app, you
所以 对 Metal SteamVR App 来说
simply wait until your command
你只需要等待 直到你的
buffer has been scheduled, and
命令缓冲被安排好
then, you can call the SteamVR
然后你就可以调用 SteamVR
PostPresentHandoff function.
PostPresentHandoff 函数了
This'll signal the VR compositor
这会告诉 VR compositor
that it can commit its work to
它可以把工作交给 GPU 了
the GPU and it'll get queued up
这一工作将按正确顺序
in the right order.
进行排队
So, let's see what that would
我们看一下
look like in your draw loop.
这在你的 draw loop 里是什么样子
So, at the top of your loop
在 loop 的顶端
you'd have your WaitGetPoses
有你的 WaitGetPoses call
call, to gather the inputs from
从头显设备里收集
the headset.
输入
You then, build your command
然后你要建立命令缓冲
buffer to render your scene and
渲染你的场景
commit it to the GPU.
然后把它提交给 GPU
And then, at this point, you'll
然后 在这里 你会
submit your left and right eye
把左右眼纹理提交给
textures to SteamVR.
SteamVR
And then, once you've waited for
然后 你等到
that command buffer to be
命令缓冲被安排好
scheduled, you can call
你就可以调用
PostPresentHandoff to tell the
PostPresentHandoff 告诉
VR compositor that it's now free
VR compositor 它现在可以
to commit work to the GPU, as
把工作交给 GPU 了
So, one more note before I move
再强调一件事
It's worth noting that as we
在我们
extend this diagram to include
把这个图表应用在
the next frame, it's
下一帧的同时 需要注意是
WaitGetPoses and not the
WaitGetPoses 而不是
vertical blank that defines the
垂直中断定义了
start of the frame for your app.
你的 App 的一帧的开始
This is an important thing to
这一点很重要
keep in mind, and we'll be
我们很快就会
coming back to this, very
回来再说到这里
All right.
好了
Let's move on to talk about some
我们接下来看一些
best practices.
很棒的实践
So, the first is to avoid
首先是要避免
introducing a GPU bubble at the
在 CPU 编码命令时
start of your frame, while
在一帧的开始产生
encoding commands on the CPU.
GPU 气泡
So, helpfully, SteamVR offers a
SteamVR 提供了一个
useful mechanism to let you
很有用的机制来
start work for that frame early,
让你很早开始这一帧的工作
by giving your app a two to
让你的 App 有
three millisecond running start.
2 到 3 毫秒的时间运行开始
So, his should look very
这应该看上去
familiar.
不陌生
By aligning the start of your
把一帧的开始
frame with WaitGetPoses, you'll
与 WaitGetPoses 对齐
ensure that you're taking
就保证了你利用到了
advantage of this optimization
这一优化
and getting that running start.
让运行开始
All right.
好的
Next, make sure that your app is
接下来 保证你的 App
not building large monolithic
不会在把它们发送给 GPU 前
command buffers before
建立大型的单片命令缓冲
committing them to the GPU, as
因为这也会
this can also introduce GPU
造成 GPU 气泡
Instead, you want to split your
你要做的是
command buffers where possible
在可能的地方分割命令缓冲
and commit them as you go, to
在进行过程中提交它们
maximize GPU utilization in the
以保证 GPU 的应用在这一帧中达到
frame.
最大化
So, the next optimization that
我们建议的下一个优化
we recommend is to try and
是尝试把你的左右眼
coalesce your left and right eye
绘制合并到一起
The Metal 2 Viewport Array
Metal 2 Viewport Array
feature provides a great
特性为你提供了一个很好的机制
mechanism for you to do this, by
帮你完成这一点
letting your app select a per
它让你的 App 在
primitive destination viewport
vertex shader （顶点着色器）里
in the vertex shader.
选择逐个几何体目标视口
This can substantially reduce
这可以大幅度
your draw call overhead, as you
降低你的 draw call 资源消耗
can now render to both the left
让你能够使用一个 draw call 来
and the right eye with a single
同时渲染左右眼场景
So, let's take a look at an
我们来看一个示例
example of how you can adopt
展示如何用 instancing 来
Viewport Array for your Metal
让你的 Metal App
app using instancing.
用上 Viewport Array
So, the first thing I want to
我要先指出
point out is that you'll need to
你需要制造一个
create a texture that's twice as
两倍宽的纹理
wide, because you'll now be
因为你现在要
rendering both the left and
用同一个纹理
right eye scene to the same
渲染左右眼场景
And then, you simply create your
然后你只需要建立你的
Viewpoint array that defines the
Viewpoint array 它定义了
bounds for your left and your
你的左右眼视口的边界
And then, you can pass this
然后你可以把这个
Viewport array to your render
Viewport array 交给你的
commanding coder using the new
渲染命令编码 你可以用
setViewports API.
setViewports API 做到这一点
And then, at this point, you'll
然后 在这里 你需要
want to make an instance to
制作一个实例到
DrawPrimitives call with an
DrawPrimitives 调用
instance count of 2 to issue the
实例数量是 2
draw to your left and right
从而把 draw 分配到左右眼
Viewports.
视口上
We'll be using the instance ID
我们会在顶点着色器里
as our eye index in the vertex
使用实例 ID 当作我们的 eye index
So, let's take a look at that
我们来看一下这个
vertex shader.
顶点着色器
So, the first thing I want to
我先要指出的是
point out is that the viewport
这个视口是
is selected by the new viewport
由新的 viewpoint_array_index
underscore array underscore
属性选择出来的
And then, as I previously noted,
我之前说过
we're using the instance
我们正在使用 instance_ID
underscore id as our eye index.
作为我们的 eye index
And we'll be able to use it to
我们将能够使用它
access our viewport dependent
访问我们的视口关联数据
data like this model view
就好像这个示例里的
projection matrix in this
这个模型投影矩阵
And then, finally, you do want
最后 一定要记得
to associate your viewport index
让你的视口索引
with the instance underscore id
和 instance_ID 关联起来
so that the right viewport is
这样在栅格化你的图像时
selected when rasterizing your
能够保证选择了正确的视口
And that's how you use the new
这就是使用新的
Viewport Array feature to reduce
Viewport Array 特性减少
the draw call cost in your VR
你的 VR App 的 draw call 开销
apps.
的方法
All right.
好了
The final optimization that I
今天我想说的最后一个优化
want to talk about, today, is
是一个公认的
really a general best practice.
最佳方法
You want to try and reduce the
你会想去尝试减少
number of pixels that you're
在每一帧着色的
shading every frame.
像素数量
So, due to the nature of the
由于镜头扭曲的特性
lens warp, about 15% of your
你渲染的场景中
rendered scene is not actually
大约 15% 的部分
visible on the VR headset.
在 VR 头显设备上是看不到的
This is represented by the blue
这幅图中的蓝色区域
regions in this image.
就代表了看不到的部分
Luckily, SteamVR offers a mesh
幸好 SteamVR 提供了一个
based stencil mask that is
基于网格的模板掩码
specific to the Vive headset
专为 Vive 头显设备设计
that you can use to cull these
你可以用它来剔除这些
pixels.
像素
It's really easy to use and
非常易用
provides a substantial benefit.
效果也非常之好
All right.
好了
That brings us to the end of our
这就是今天这个
brief journey into building a VR
构建 VR App 的简短介绍的全部内容
So, with that background
背景介绍完毕
covered, I'd like to now
我想请 Valve 软件公司的
introduce Nat Brown from Valve
Nat Brown 上台
Software, to come onstage and
为大家深入讲解
talk a bit more about SteamVR on
macOS 系统上的 SteamVR
[ Applause ]
[掌声]
Thanks, Nat.
谢谢 Nat
&gt;&gt; Thanks, Rav.
&gt;&gt; 谢谢 Rav
Hi, everybody.
嗨 大家好
I'm Nat. I work on VR at Valve.
我是 Nat 在 Valve 负责 VR 工作
So, if you don't know Valve,
如果你们还不知道 Valve
we're a game company.
我们是个游戏公司
We distribute games and we have
我们发行游戏
a community of gamers that play
我们在 Steam 上有
on Steam.
许多玩家
It turns out, games are actually
实践证明 游戏
a super-interesting crucible for
对于用户界面
user interface and
和人机交互来说
human/computer interaction.
是一个非常有趣的严峻考验
And at Valve, we do a lot of
在 Valve 我们围绕着
experiments around games and
游戏和输入 进行了很多
input.
实验
So, years of VR prototypes
但多年来的 VR 原形体
really didn't click, for us, for
却并没有真正适用在
making games or any other kind
制作游戏或者其他任何内容上面
Until we found this sweet
知道我们发现了这个
combination of 90 hertz low
完美的结合体
persistence displays, accurate
包括 90 赫兹低余辉显示
room scale tracking, with two
以及用这两个追踪控制器实现的
track controllers.
房间范围内的准确追踪
We consider this a magical
我们认为这就是 VR 领域的
threshold for VR.
神奇突破
I like to think of it as kind of
我想它可以与
similar to how when you first
你第一次使用
used a smartphone with low
低延迟精确触屏的
latency accurate touch, it
智能手机的感受相比
really felt magical.
感觉非常神奇
That's what this magical
这就是 VR 领域的
threshold is, for VR.
神奇突破
Once room scale VR really
一旦房间大小的 VR 环境
clicked for us, we knew that we
成为了现实 我们就知道自己终于可以
could build VR games and VR
构建 VR 游戏和 VR
content.
内容了
We license aspects of our VR
我们授权了各方面的 VR
technology like base stations,
技术 比如基站
headset lens designs, and so
头显设备镜片设计等等
forth, non-exclusively to
非独家地授权给了
partners like HTC and LG.
HTC 和 LG 等等合作伙伴
And we have a big program that
我们还有一个大型项目
licenses Lighthouse tracking
把 Lighthouse 追踪技术
technology to lots of different
授权给了很多不同的合作伙伴
Our approach to the software
我们对于软件栈的办法
stack you've heard a little bit
你们也许已经听说了
about, already, is called the
那就是
SteamVr runtime.
SteamVr runtime
SteamVr has an application
SteamVr 有一个应用模型
model, up above, and a hardware
在上面 和一个硬件
and driver model, down below.
与驱动模型 在下面
Our goal here, is to promote
我们的目标是
experiments in VR, because we're
大力推广 VR 领域的实践
really in the early days of what
因为我们现在还处于
VR is and what the content's
VR 初期 还不了解它
going to be like.
能够发展成什么样子
We wanted to make this model so
我们想制作这个模型
that people could experiment in
让人们在里面实验
VR hardware and content and
VR 硬件和内容 同时
reduce risk.
减少风险
So, you can go out, maybe not
你们可以去
you, but some of you can go out
也许不是你们 但总有人可以去
and design a new headset or a
设计新的头显设备
new tracking system, or new
新的追踪系统 新的
controllers.
控制器
And then, you can come to an
然后 你们可以到
Open VR platform, and you can
Open VR 平台上
write a driver that plugs right
写一个驱动程序然后直接插入设备
And you'll have access to all
然后你就可以访问
the existing content that's
正在运行的
already running.
所有内容了
That will give you real world
这会给你真实世界的
tests that make your hardware
测试 能让你的硬件变得
better.
更好
Because you and your customers
因为你和你的顾客
can compare your new idea
可以直接将你的新创意
directly with other hardware
和其他在这个平台上的
that's already out there.
硬件进行对比
So, hardware developers don't
这样一来 硬件开发者就不必
have to develop custom content
开发特定内容
and content developers don't
内容开发者也不必
have to bet on which hardware
去赌哪一个硬件
will win.
会胜出了
They can just focus on making
他们只需要集中精力
great content.
做好内容就可以了
So, applications link to the
下面讲到关联到
Open VR framework.
Open VR 框架的应用
It's a really tiny library, and
这是一个很小的库
all it knows how to do is define
它只知道去定义
the runtime that's currently
当前被安装的 runtime
installed.
它找到这个 VR 用户库
library, that's a shared
这是一个共享库
library, and that either
它要么能够关联到
connects to or launches the
要么能够启动
other runtime processes of
SteamVR 的其他 runtime
SteamVr.
进程
The vrmonitor process.
这是 vrmonitor 进程
You're going to see a lot of
你们会看到许多
that little window.
这样的小窗口
It's a UI and a setting
这是一个 UI 和设置
application.
应用
It shows you the state of any
它会显示连接
attached headsets and
头显设备和控制器
controllers, and the tracking
以及追踪感应器的
sensors.
状态
The vrserver is in charge of
vrserver 负责
keeping track of drivers,
追踪驱动
loading alternate drivers.
加载交替驱动
And it puts poses and other
它还会把姿态和其他信息
information into shared memory.
放入共享内存
So, that your application and
以便让你的应用
the rest of the SteamVR runtime
和 SteaVR runtime 的其他部分
have access to it.
能够访问它
The vrcompositor, you just heard
这是 vrcompositor 你们刚刚
a little bit about, this process
已经稍微了解过了
is sort of like the Windows
这个进程有点像
server.
Windows Server
It draws scenes and overlays to
它把场景和 overlay 绘制在
the headset.
头显设备上
And it corrects images for lens
它还会根据镜片失真和颜色
distortion, color.
来矫正图像
And one of the things that's
还有一件从某种程度来看
sort of under the hood, that you
是隐藏起来的 你们可能
may not understand, is it
不太明白的事 那就是它还
corrects for smearing and
会矫正动态画面中的
ghosting under motion.
拖尾和重影
And it also, fades into a stable
它还会在应用无法
tracking area when applications
达到帧率时
fail to meet frame rate.
消失在稳定跟踪区域
Because we don't want people to
因为我们不想让人们
fall over or bump into
碰到一些意外情况
So, the vrcompositor
vrcompositor
communicates with Metal, like
与 Metal 进行通讯
you heard.
你们已经了解过了
It presents directly to the
它通过 Direct to Display
headset through the Direct to
Metal 2 API
Display Metal 2 API.
把画面直接显示在头显设备上
Let's see.
我们看一下
Last, but not least, the mighty
最后要说的是
vrdashboard.
vrdashboard
That is a piece of UI that lets
这部分的 UI 让你
you select applications.
能够选择应用
It lets you control volume,
让你控制音量
other system settings.
等其他系统设置
We provide a default one that
我们提供一个默认的
shows you your Steam library,
向你展示你的 Steam 库
unless you choose applications.
除非你选择应用
But there's actually an API.
但实际上有一个 API
So, you can write your own
你也可以写你自己的
dashboard application, as well.
dashboard 应用
So, Valve and Apple, we started
Valve 和 Apple 我们已经
working together more closely,
更加密切地合作
about a year ago.
就在大约一年前开始
And our port to Metal from
我们把端口从 OpenGL 转换到 Metal
OpenGL, it didn't cost us very
并没有让我们花费太多代价
much.
Metal 是个非常酷的 API
And it was critical for us to
它对于我们实现 VR 的高性能运行
get VR up and performing.
起到了关键作用
Our biggest request to Apple, a
大约一年前 我们对 Apple 最大的要求
year ago, was for this Direct to
就是这个 Direct to
Display feature.
Display 的特性
Because it's critical to ensure
因为要确保
that the VR compositor has the
VR compositor 有达到头显设备的
fastest time predictable path to
最快的可预测通道
the headset display panels.
这非常重要
We also, really needed super
同时我们还非常需要
accurate low variance VBL,
非常准确的低方差 VBL
vertical blank, events.
也就是垂直中断事件
So, that we could set the
这样我们就可以设置
cadence of the VR frame
VR 显示帧的节拍
presentation timing, and we
并且可以
could predict those poses
精确预测
accurately.
这些动作
Predicting the pose accurately
精确预测动作
is actually more important than
实际上要比动作发生之间的时间
the time between motion happens
和显示出现的时间
and when the display happens.
更为重要
If we know when it's going to
如果我们知道什么时候会发生
be, that's actually more
那是更加重要的
Finally, we hit some speed bumps
最后 我们在进程
around inter-process and
和线程之间的同步方面
inter-thread synchronization.
遇到了一些阻碍
Once everything else was working
其他一切都运行良好
really well, Metal was blazing
Metal 速度很快
fast, we had really tight VBL,
我们也有了超精确低方差 VBL
but we still were having some
但还是存在一些
synchronization problems.
同步方面的问题
But Apple helped us find better
不过 Apple 帮助我们找到了
ways to signal and synchronize
更好的方法去发送信号
with low scheduling variance
和在所有的进程与线程之间
between all the processes and
进行低调速差异的
thread involved.
同步
Okay. So, my diagram of a VR
我这个 VR 帧的图表
frame is a little more
比较复杂
Most of you are never going to
你们中的大多数人
look under the hood, this far.
永远不会看到这么深
But I thought I'd show it to
但我还是想给你们
you, anyway.
看一看
So, the low persistence OLED of
HTC Vibe 的
the HTC Vibe uses global
低余辉 OLED 显示屏使用了
illumination.
全局照明
All of the pixels of the display
显示图像上的所有像素
flash for a tiny period, all at
都会在同时在极短时间内闪烁
once.
这在 VR 中很常见
because heads move really
因为头部动作
quickly.
很快
And we want to make sure that
我们要保证
the image doesn't smear or tear
画面不会在用户眼前
in front of the user.
产生拖尾或者撕裂
So, the panel illuminates for
panel 会照亮
about two milliseconds, one
大约 2 毫秒每帧
frame after it is presented by
在它被 GPU 显示之后
the GPU, because the panel takes
因为 panel 需要时间
time to charge before it can do
去充能 然后才可以
that global illumination pulse.
发出全局照明脉冲
So, over here, that's the
这里 光子就从
photons coming out.
这里出来
We're going to follow this red
我们要在这个序列中
frame through this sequence.
跟踪这个红框
So, way out here is the photons
光子在这里
coming out.
被释放出来
Because of this timing,
因为这个时机
applications typically pick up a
应用通常会选择一个动作
pose, like you heard before,
就像大家已经知道的一样
from IVR compositor wakeup
应用从 IVR compositor 唤醒动作里
poses.
选择一个动作
So, wakeup poses stalls and
唤醒动作会延迟
returns with a pose for that
并为那个未来的光子释放
future firing of photons.
发回一个动作
So, the rendering is happening
这里是渲染
here, and you present it there,
你把它显示在那里
here in the middle.
在中间这里
But the photons don't go out
但光子不会从那里
there.
出去
So, we've had to predict a pose
所以我们必须要
about 25 milliseconds out.
预测 25 毫秒之后的动作
So, 25 milliseconds is two
25 毫秒是
frames plus the little tiny bit
两帧再加上运行开始时
of running start.
那一瞬间
And you heard how running
你们已经知道
start's very important, because
运行开始是非常重要的
we want to give you as much of
我们想要尽可能地
that 11 milliseconds of GPU to
给你们那 11 毫秒 GPU 时间
get the most excellent pixels up
去给用户展现
in front of the users, that you
最好的画面
can.
最后发生的事
happening, here.
在这里
You see this frame actually
你们可以看到这一帧
stretches back all the way to
会延伸到
the beginning of the slide.
一开始的地方
And that's because this
那是因为这个应用
application, and your game
比较复杂
engine might be doing this under
你的游戏引擎
the covers, is kind of more
可能会在暗中这样做
It has some physics and input
它需要处理
event processing, that it needs
一些物理和输入事件
And that's costly work that's
在这里
going to take some CPU time,
这个工作需要占用
over here.
一些 CPU 时间
But that code actually needs
那个代码实际上也需要
pose information, also.
动作信息
It needs to know when the
它需要知道
buttons were pressed and where
什么时候按键了
the controllers were.
控制器在哪里
Maybe it's interpolating
也许它正在插入
something having to do with
一些关于动作的东西
motion, or you're blocking
或者你在阻挡一些东西
something, or you're firing
或者你在发射一些东西
So, this thread actually, it's
所以 实际上这个线程
going to wake up at around the
它会在差不多同时唤醒
same time, because wakeup poses
因为唤醒动作
gives it this important kind of
给了它这个重要的
synch point.
同步点
But it's going to be calling a
但它会调用
different API, because it's
一个不同的 API
trying to get a pose much
因为它正试着获得
further out.
一个更远的动作
It's looking 36 milliseconds
36 毫秒之后
out, and so, it's going to be
所以它需要
calling the getDevice to
调用 getDevice
absolute tracking poses.
来精确追踪动作
So, I tell you this just so you
我说这些是为了让你们知道
know, Open VR has some pretty
OpenVR 有一些
deep APIs for you to tune your
很深的 API 让你们用来
applications so that you're
调试你们的应用
predicting where the headset and
让你们能够精确预测
where the controllers are going
头显设备和控制器
to be very accurately, based on
将会在哪里
where you need them to be, where
基础就是你需要它们在哪里
your code needs them to be.
你的代码需要它们在哪里
So, the point of wakeup poses is
唤醒动作的意义就在于
it gives you a predictable point
它在运行开始时就及时
in time at running start, so you
给你一个预测点
always know when those photons
你就会知道这些光子
are going to come out.
何时会释放出来
So, last but not least, let's
最后让我们说一说
talk about what you need to do
你需要做什么
to get up and running with
来使用
SteamVr and macOS.
SteamVr 和 macOS
So, first of all, it's a tool in
首先 这是 Steam 上的一个工具
Steam, as a developer gets
开发者需要安装
started by installing Steam and
Steam 并注册免费账户
registering for a free account.
才能开始
And if you don't use Steam, you
如果你们还没有使用 Steam
should.
快开始用吧
Next, install SteamVR itself.
接下来是安装 SteamVR 本身
SteamVR is under the Library
SteamVR 在工具中的
menu in Tools.
Library 菜单里
Search for SteamVR, right click
搜索 SteamVR 右键点击
on it, choose the Properties,
选择 Properties
choose the Beta tab, and opt
选择 Beta
into the Beta.
进入 Beta
For now, it's a beta.
现在还是 beta 版本
Then, install it.
然后安装它
We'll be keeping SteamVr up to
我们会保持 SteamVR 的更新
date as we fix any bugs that you
你们发现 bug 后我们就会去修复
Finally, you want to download
最后 你们要去 GitHub
the Open VR headers and the
下载 OpenVR header 和
framework from GitHub.
框架
And I've put a link, right up
我在这里放了一个链接
So, here's the funky part.
这是最酷的部分
You need to include that Open VR
你要把 OpenVR
bootstrapping framework inside
bootstrapping 框架
of your application.
放到你的应用里
The Open VR framework that you
你链接到的 OpenVR 框架
link to, that conveys the
表达了你构建
version of the interfaces of the
并测试的
runtime you've built and tested
runtime 界面的版本
And that allows us to upgrade
这会让我们能
the runtime and to version
升级 runtime 和进行
forward, gracefully.
版本更新
Because we move this forward
我们会很积极地
quite actively.
进行更新
In XCode, instead of just adding
在 Xcode 里 不要去把框架
the framework to your link
添加到你的 link phase
phase, go into General Settings
而应该到通用设置里
and make it an embedded binary.
把它设置成 embedded binary （嵌入式二进制文件）
So, it will be installed into
它会被安装到
the contents frameworks portion
你的应用程序包里的
of your application bundle.
内容框架部分
Okay. Finally, we really want
好了 最后 我们真的需要
your feedback.
你们的反馈
So, we put some things right
因此 我们直接在
into the UI of vrmonitor.
vrmonitor 的 UI 里放了一些东西
There's a pointer to SteamVR's
有个指针可以直接到 SteamVR 的
support site and the community
支持网站和硬件
hardware discussions.
讨论群
And you can report a bug, create
你可以上报 bug
a system report, and send it to
制作系统报告并
us or probably send it to me.
发送给我们 也可以直接发到我手上
You can reach me at
我的邮箱地址是
natb@valvesoftware.com, but I'd
natb@valvesoftware.com
rather you use the tool.
不过我更希望你们使用这个工具
And with that, thanks very much.
非常感谢大家
I'm really looking forward to
我真的很期待看到
what you guys make with VR.
你们使用 VR 的工作成果
And thanks, to everybody at
还要谢谢 Apple 的每个人
Apple for making VR shine on
让 VR 在 macOS 上发光
Thank you.
谢谢大家
[ Applause ]
[掌声]
&gt;&gt; Thanks, Nat.
&gt;&gt; 谢谢 Nat
It's been great working with
与 Valve 合作非常愉快
Valve, and I'm still astounded
此时此刻 我仍然
about what we've been able to
震惊于我们在过去一年
achieve, over the last year.
所取得的成绩
All right.
好了
Let's move on to talk about the
我们接着谈谈
external GPU support that we've
我们在 macOS High Sierra 里添加的
added with macOS High Sierra.
外接 GPU 支持吧
So, an external GPU is a
外接 GPU 是一个
standalone chassis with a
独立的底盘 上面
desktop class GPU in it, that
有个桌面级别的 GPU
you can plug directly to your
可以通过 thunderbolt
host system via Thunderbolt.
直接插到主系统上
And as noted previously, the
之前说过
primary motivation here, was to
这样做的主要原因
enable developers like you to
是让你们这样的开发者能够
build great VR apps using a
使用更多样的 Mac 硬件
broader range of Mac hardware.
去制作更出色的 VR App
There's a great workflow story,
这是个很棒的 workflow
here, where you can use your
你可以用你的 MacBook Pro
MacBook Pro with an external GPU
和外接 GPU
to get the rendering horsepower
来获得制作 VR 应用所需的
that you need for VR.
渲染性能
But of course, there's also
当然 这还能为
additional performance benefit
其他 GPU 应用场景
to be had for other GPU bound
提供额外的性能支持
cases, like games and pro apps,
比如游戏和专业 App
And as you saw on Monday, we've
大家在周一了解过了
been partnering with Sonnet and
我们和 Sonnet 与 AMD 合作
AMD to offer you an external
为你们提供了一个
graphics developer kit with an
外部图像开发者套装
AMD Radeon RX-580 GPU in it.
里面有一块 AMD Radeon RX-580 GPU
This kit is optimized for use
这个套装已经优化过
with all our Thunderbolt 3
适配所有的能兼容 Thunderbolt3
capable Macs, and is available
的 Mac 设备
for purchase through our
今天就能通过开发者计划
developer program, today.
购买这个套装
All right.
好了
Let's dive right into how you
接下来讲要如何
identify the external GPU.
识别外接 GPU
This device enumeration code
这个设备枚举代码
should look very familiar to
看上去应该很不陌生
CopyAllDevices will give you all
CopyAllDevices 会显示出
the Metal devices in the system.
系统中所有支持 Metal 的设备
And then, you can identify the
然后你可以识别出
external GPU by simply looking
外部 GPU 了 方法就是
for the removable property in
识别设备的
the device.
可删除属性就可以了
This is very similar to how you
这和你们之前
previously identified the low
识别我们平台上的
power devices on our platforms.
低电量设备的方法很类似
Now, let's talk a bit about
现在 我们来稍微讲一下
Thunderbolt bandwidth
Thunderbolt 带宽功能
So, Thunderbolt 3 offers twice
Thunderbolt 3 提供的
the theoretical bandwidth of
理论带宽是
Thunderbolt 2, which is great.
Thunderbolt 2 的两倍 这很好
But you have to keep in mind
但不要忘了
that this is still a quarter the
这只不过是
bandwidth of the PCI bus
我们平台上
available to the internal GPUs
内置 GPU 总线驱动带宽
in our platforms.
的四分之一而已
So, this is important.
这很重要
You have a choice, now, between
你现在可以选择
using the internal GPU with a
是使用带宽更高的
high bandwidth link, or a high
内置 GPU
performance external GPU with a
还是使用大约
link at about a quarter the
四分之一带宽的
bandwidth.
高性能外接 GPU
So, you need to treat the link
在决定使用哪个 GPU 的时候
and the GPU as a pair when
要把带宽的因素
deciding which GPU you use.
也考虑进去
Additionally, users can now
此外 用户现在可以
attach displays to different
在不同的 GPU 上接不同的显示设备了
GPUs.
在这个环境下
a penalty to render on one GPU
要使用一个 GPU 渲染
and then, display on another, as
另一个 GPU 显示的话 就会有个缺点
that date needs to be
因为数据需要
transferred across the link.
通过链接传输
So, where your content is
所以 内容会在哪里显示
displayed clearly is a huge
这是你在决定使用哪个 GPU 时
consideration when you decide
必须要考虑的
which GPU you want to use, as
一个重要因素
So, there's additional
这添加了一些
complexity, here.
复杂性
But fortunately, there's a
但幸好
couple simple things that you
你可以做一点
can do to make your app a good
简单的事情 让你的 App
citizen in a multi-GPU
在多 GPU 环境下
environment.
表现良好
So, let's start with GPU
我们先讲 GPU 的选择
The best advice that we can give
我们强烈建议
you is to render on the same GPU
你使用同一块 GPU
that's driving the display your
渲染和驱动你 App 的
app is on.
显示设备
I call this the golden rule of
我把这称为 GPU 选择的
GPU selection.
黄金法则
So, let's extend this and build
我们展开一下
a decision tree.
制作一个决策树
So, if the content your app is
如果你的 App 渲染的内容
rendering will be presented to a
会被显示出来
display, you want to select the
你就要去选择
GPU that's driving that display.
驱动那个显示设备的 GPU
This is our golden rule.
这是我们的黄金法则
However, if your app is doing
但是如果你的 App
compute or other offline
要进行计算或者其他
rendering operations, then you
离线渲染操作
need to decide if you prefer to
那你就要决定是否要
use the low power GPU is it's
使用低能耗 GPU 了
available.
如果可能的话
This can be particularly useful
这在移动设备上
on our portables, where
尤其有用
selecting this device can have a
因为选择这个设备
substantial battery savings.
会极大地节省电量
But of course, if you need the
但当然 如果你
GPU horsepower for things like
需要把 GPU 性能用在 VR 上面
VR, you're going to want to
你就得选择
select the external GPU.
外接 GPU 了
So, let's get back to our golden
我们回到黄金法则上
rule and find out how you
看看要如何
identify the Metal device that's
识别驱动特定显示的
driving a particular display.
Metal 设备吧
Well, it turns out that this is
你们会发现
really easy to do.
这是很容易的
There's an existing core
有一个现有的
graphics API that will give you
图像 API 会让你
this device.
识别这个设备
You simply have to get the ID
你只需要得到你的窗口
for the display that your window
所在的显示设备的 ID
is on, by querying the
方法就是去询问
NSScreenNumber.
NSScreenNumber
And then, call
然后调用
CGDirectDisplayCopyCurrentMetal
CGDirectDisplayCopyCurrentMetalDevice
Device to get the Metal device
来获取驱动这个显示的
that's driving that display.
Metal 设备
It's that simple.
就这么简单
All right.
好了
Now, that we've established that
我们已经知道
each display can be attached to
每个显示设备
a different GPU, your app will
都可以接到不同的 GPU 上
need to handle GPU migration as
你的 App 就需要在显示移动时
your displays are moved.
操作 GPU 的迁移
Sorry, as your window is moved
不好意思 我是说在你的窗口
across those displays.
在这些显示中移动的时候
So, you can do that by
你可以通过
registering for the new, well,
注册新的
it's not new, our existing
其实不是新的 是我们已有的
notification handler called
通知管理 叫做
WindowDidChangeScreen.
WindowDidChangeScreen 来实现这一点
So, let's take a look at what
我们看一看你们要
you do with this notification
如何处理这个通知管理
So, you'll want to start by
首先要找到
finding the Metal device for the
你的 App 现在所在的显示的
display your app is now on, by
Metal 设备 方法就是
calling the core graphics API
调用我们刚才说过的
that we previously discussed.
核心图像 API
You can early out if it's the
如果这就是你当前正在
same device that you're
渲染的同一个设备
currently rendering to, since no
那你就能提前完成了
GPU migration will be required.
因为不需要 GPU 迁移
And then, you'll want to perform
然后 你要进行
your device migration and switch
设备迁移
to using the new device for all
切换到使用新设备
your rendering.
进行所有渲染
So, that's how you use a display
这就是使用显示
change notification to handle
更改通知来操作
GPU migration.
GPU 迁移
But what about the case where
但外接 GPU
the external GPU is plugged in,
插入系统
or unplugged from your system?
或者拔出系统时该怎样呢
Well, Metal 2 introduces three
Metal 2 推出了
new notifications to help you
3 个新通知 在这种情况下
with this case.
帮助你
These are DeviceWasAdded when an
第一个是 DeviceWasAdded
external GPU was plugged in,
适用于外接 GPU 插入时
DeviceWasRemoved when it's
DeviceWasRemoved 适用于
unplugged, and
拔出时
DeviceRemovalRequested when the
还有 DeviceRemovalRequested
OS signals an intent to remove a
适用于 OS 准备在未来某个时间点
GPU at some point in the future.
移除外接 GPU 的情况
So, let's take a look at how you
我们看看你要如何
would register for, and then,
注册并响应
respond to these notifications.
这些通知
So, you'll want to use the new
你要使用新的
CopyAllDevicesWithObserver API
CopyAllDevicesWithObserver API
that we've introduced with Metal
这是我们在 Metal 2 中新推出的
This will let you register a
这会让你为这些新的
handler for these new device
设备变更通知注册
change notifications.
handler
In this case, we're simply
在这个示例里
invoking a function called
我们只需要调用一个叫
handleGPUHotPlug.
handleGPUHotPlug 的函数
So, let's take a look at it.
我们来看一看
It's really straightforward.
这真的很简单直接
All you have to do is check for
你只需要检查
and directly respond to each
并直接回应每一条通知
But I want to point out a couple
但我想在这里
of things, here.
指出几件事
The first is that your app
首先 你的 App
should treat the
应该把
DeviceRemovalRequested
DeviceRemovalRequested
notification as a hint to start
通知 当成要迁移出
migrating off the external GPU.
外接 GPU 的提示
And second, if your app did not
第二 如果你的 App
receive the
没有接收到
DeviceRemovalRequested
DeviceRemovalRequested
notification, then it should
通知 那它就应该
treat DeviceWasRemoved as an
把 DeviceWasRemoved 当成
unexpected GPU removal.
意外的 GPU 移除
So, an unexpected GPU removal is
意外的 GPU 移除是指
when your external GPU is
你的外接 GPU 在系统不知情的情况下
disconnected or powered down
切断了连接
without the OS being aware.
或者失去了电力
So, this is the equivalent of
这就等于
somebody reaching into your
有人进入了你的系统
system and yanking out that GPU.
拔掉了 GPU
And since the hardware is no
既然硬件已经
longer there, some Metal API
不在了 一些 Metal API
calls will start returning
调用就会开始出现错误
So, you'll want to add defensive
因此你需要在 App 中
code to your app to protect
添加防护代码
against this.
以防这种情况发生
So, it can survive until it
让它能够坚持住
receives a migration
直到收到迁移通知
notification and it can
并从容地
gracefully switch to another GPU
切换到系统中的
in the system.
另一块 GPU 上
It's also worth pointing out
还有一点需要指出
that if you had any transient
那就是如果你在外接 GPU 的
data on the external GPU's local
本地内存上有临时数据
memory, your app may need to
你的 App 就可能需要
regenerate this, as it's no
重新生成数据 因为它
longer there.
已经没有了
All right.
好了
Now, on to some best practices.
现在讲一些最佳实践
So, we recommend that you don't
我们建议你们
immediately release devices
不要在迁移后立即
after you migrate, as users tend
释放设备
to move windows back and forth
因为用户喜欢在不同显示设备之间
across displays.
移动窗口
Instead, employ a lazy teardown
所以请
policy with some reasonable
采用延迟 teardown 策略 留出一些合理时间
Additionally, if your app has a
此外 如果你的 App
complex UI with a number of
有复杂的 UI 有很多窗口
windows, you may, may, need to
你也许 也许需要
handle GPU migrations separately
分别针对每个窗口
for each window.
控制 GPU 迁移
And then, finally, we recommend
最后 我们建议
that you profile your app in
你在多 GPU 场景下
multi-GPU situations, to ensure
存储 App 以保证
that you're not needlessly
你不需要
transferring data back and
在 GPU 之间来回传送数据
forth, across the GPUs.
做无用功
All right.
好了
Let's tie it back to VR with
我们回到 VR 上来
some best practices specific to
看一看这种使用场景下的
this use case.
最佳实践
First and most obvious, make
首先 最明显的
sure you attach the VR headset
保证你把 VR 头显设备
directly to the external GPU.
直接插到外接 GPU 上
Less obvious, but equally
不那么明显但同样重要的是
important, you want to make sure
你要确保你的 App
that your app is presenting its
把它的 UI 或是
UI or the mirrored VR content to
镜像 VR 内容
a display that's also being
显示到同样被
driven by the external GPU.
外接 GPU 驱动的显示器上
This will ensure that both the
这会确保
VR compositor and your app are
VR compositor 和你的 App
rendering with the external GPU.
都使用外接 GPU 进行渲染
And finally, make sure you cache
最后 要保证你
as many resources as possible on
在外接 GPU 的本地内存上
the external GPU's local memory,
存储尽可能多的数据
so that you're not streaming
这样你就不需要通过
data across the Thunderbolt
Thunderbolt 链接传输数据了
link, unless absolutely
除非这是绝对必要的
All right.
好了
So, this brings us to the end of
这就是今天讲座的
our session.
全部内容
So, let's quickly review what
我们来快速回顾一下
we've covered, today.
今天谈到的东西
So, the big news is that you can
最重要的是你们现在
now, develop VR content on
可以在 macOS 上开发 VR 内容了
We've added built-in support for
我们添加了对 HTC Vibe 头显设备的
the HTC Vibe headset.
内置支持
And we've partnered with Valve
我们与 Valve 合作
to enable an optimized version,
为在我们平台上的 SteamVR
an optimized Metal version of
runtime 推出了一个
the SteamVR runtime on our
优化版本的 Metal
Additionally, two of the most
此外 两个最流行的
popular game engines, Unity and
游戏引擎 Unity
Unreal Engine 4 will be bringing
和虚幻 4 会在不久的将来
VR support to the Mac, in the
在 Mac 中加入 VR 支持
But of course, we also encourage
但当然 我们也鼓励
you to build your own native VR
你们构建自己的原生 VR
app.
App
And finally, we added support
最后 我们还添加了
for external GPUs.
对外接 GPU 的支持
And we hope that this motivates
我们希望这能
you to ensure that your app is a
让你保证你的 App
good citizen in a multi-GPU
在多 GPU 环境下
environment, so that you can
表现良好
take advantage of that
让你们能利用上
additional GPU horsepower.
外接 GPU 的强劲性能
We're really excited to see what
我们非常期待看到
you guys are going to be able to
你们使用这个新技术
build with this new technology.
创造出的成果
So, be sure to check out the
一定要记得去
other sessions on the Metal
看 Metal Track 的
Track.
其他讲座
We had a great Introducing Metal
昨天有一场很棒的
2 session, yesterday.
Introducing Metal 2 讲座
If you didn't get a chance to
如果你们没赶上
see it, I encourage you to watch
我建议你们去上网
the video online.
看一看
We have two additional sessions
我们明天下午
in the afternoon, tomorrow,
还有两场讲座
Metal 2 Optimization and
Metal 2 Optimization and
Debugging, and Using Metal 2 for
Debugging 和 Using Metal 2 for
Compute.
Compute
We hope to see you, there.
我们希望在那里见到你们
I'll see you, there.
我会去的
Thank you, very much, and have a
非常感谢大家
great WWDC.
祝你们在 WWDC 大有收获
[ Applause ]
[掌声]